Karishma Saini

♀ 7 Huron Rd, Yonkers, NY, 10710, USA **ເ** ksaini7595@gmail.com **** 914-433-7691

in linkedin.com/in/karishma-saini

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Financial Information Systems, Pace University Graduate Assistant

May 2018 - May 2020 | Valhalla, USA

- Constructed, updated, and maintained user guides, training and SOPs (Standard Operating Procedure) documentation for company's operating systems, software, and tools.
- Monitored all web content, fixed technical errors, ensured smooth functioning of Pace University website with HTML and CSS under Drupal CMS.
- Provided technical expertise and updates in code reviews and application discussions.
- Assisted in development and maintenance of an API for integration with PHP and SQL.
- Knowledge of remote desktop connections, peer to peer file sharing and other applications associated with remote IT assistance.
- Responsible for handling clients' requests using the help desk ticketing system and phone calls

Information Technology Support, Pace University

ITS Desk Assistant

Sep 2015 - May 2018

- Provide technical support for 10-12 students, faculty or staff.
- Evaluate equipment in order to access technical issues such as connection with the WiFi or/and printers.

kHinky.com

Web Developer Intern

May 2017 - Jul 2017 | Bronx, USA

- Responsible for developing a website using the content management system to showcase the company's products to increase sales.
- Created additional pages for the website to enhance visitors' experiences.

GenCyber

Computer Lab Intern

Jun 2016 - Jul 2016 | Pleasantvilla, USA

- Set up and supported a learning lab for the Raspberry Pi for teachers to use for their labs.
- These labs encouraged teachers to use Raspberry Pi for their academic curriculum.

PROFILE

Frontend Developer and UX Designer with a passion for web application development and success in creating user interactive prototypes Agile processes. Experienced in technical writing, building user stories, and developing responsive web pages. Dedicate to provide innovative methods with the ability to follow technological trends and to achieve the organization's goal.

EDUCATION

Pace University, Seidenberg School of Computer Science and Information Systems

Master of Science (MS) in Information Technology | Concentration: Cybersecurity 2018 – 2020

Pace University, Seidenberg School of Computer Science and Information Systems

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science 2014 – 2018 | Pleasantville, USA

SKILLS

Frontend

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Semantic UI, Material UI Bootstrap 4, Tachyons

Content Management Systems

Drupal, Shopify, Wix, Wordpress

Backend

Express, node, SQL, PHP, Postgres, Mongo DB

Version Control

Git/GitHub, BitBucket, SourceTree

Microsoft Suite

Word, Excel, PowerPoint, OneDrive, OutLook, Visio

Software Tools

inVision Studio, Visual Studio Code Editor, Sublime Editor, Adobe Captivate

UX Designer

Wireframes, User Research, Interactive Design, Task Flows, User Stories,

AWARDS

Alpha Chi

Golden Key International Honour Society

Dean's list

Alpha Lambda Delta

Lambda Sigma